Party is over
それでも踊りたかった
But I still wanna dance
眠れないくらい
I can't even sleep
情熱の火はいつしか　いつの日にか
Someday, one day my passion's fire will
はなから気付いている
From the beginning I knew
炎はいつか消える
One day the flames would die out
何も要らないはずだった
Hey, I thought I didn't need anything
なのにまだ I'm so serious
But even now, I'm so serious
ああ　まだ間に合う
Ah... I still have time to make it
ああ ただ Burn it up Baby
Ah... but I'm gonna burn it up, baby
Sorry darling そんなに甘くないよ
Sorry darling, it's not that easy
でもきっとそんなに悪くないよ
But surely it's not that bad either
ああ Give me fire!
Give me fire
Light it up Baby 燃やしちゃうぜ
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
Party is over
Sorry darling Hurry up
Ah... I still have time to make it
ああただBurn it up
Sorry darling Hurry up
Ah... I still have time to make it
Give me fire
Light it up Baby 燃やしちゃうぜ
Light it up, baby.
I'm gonna burn it up, yeah
#5 The story of the Moriko Song, part 1
あにき！
Hey!
Hyakkimaru.
あにき…
Hey.
大丈夫か
You okay?
ここでもダメなのかよ…
Still too noisy for you, huh?
静かすぎて怖いくらいだけどな
But it's so quiet here it creeps me out.
音
Sound.
それは百鬼丸が取り戻したどの感覚よりも衝撃だった
It was the most shocking sense
that Hyakkimaru had so far recovered.
容赦なく頭の中に入り込んでくる
It reverberated relentlessly in his head.
無数の振動の取捨選択など、できるはずもなく
He knew not how to select which of
the innumerable sounds to listen to.
百鬼丸はただ音の洪水に溺れていた
Hyakkimaru drowned in the flood of sound.
あにき、やっぱり今回のあやかし退治はやめとこうか
Hey, maybe we should give up on
going after the next monster.
礼金いいから勿体ねぇけど、こんな調子じゃ…
The reward is handsome,
but you're just not fit for it.
出たのか？
Is something there?
来た！鳥のあやかし、でけぇ！
The bird monster! It's huge!
あにき！音なんか気にすんな！
Hyakkimaru, don't worry about the sound!
左だ！
Your left!
あにき！
Watch out!
坊さん！
Priest!
おや 坊やたちだったかい 奇遇だねぇ
Oh, it was you two? What a coincidence.
あにき あにき？
Hey, hey.
しっかりしてくれよ！あにき！
Come on, snap out of it.
あにき、あにき！
What's wrong with you?
おい！
Hey...
そうかい、耳がねぇ。そいつはよかったじゃないか
I see, his ears eh? Good for him.
よくなんかねぇ
It's not good.
聞こえるようになったせいであにき、弱くなちまった
He's gotten weaker now that he can hear.
そうかい？
How so?
だって、坊さんでもあんな簡単にやっつけられる
あやかしにこんなにやられちまってさ…
I mean, he got beat up by that ghoul
that even you could kill.
こいつはごあいさつだ！
Well, thank you.
なぁ…あにき、大丈夫だよな…
He'll be all right, won't he?
急場は凌いだよ
He's gotten past the worst of it.
本当なら薬が欲しいとこじゃあるんだが
We could use some medicine,
if only we had any.
おいら、ひとっ走り行ってこようか？
I'll go run and find some.
川向こうに大きな町があるはずだ！
There's a big town across the river.
およし どうやら戦がありそうだからね 危ないよ
You better not. I heard
there's a war brewing. It's dangerous.
え？
この辺りを治める酒井って武将が 同盟国を裏切ったとかでね
Seems like the Sakai clan,
who rules this area, betrayed an ally.
2つの軍が睨み合いさね
The 2 armies have their swords drawn.
そんなとこにあたしらみたいなよそ者が近づくのは剣呑だ
For strangers like us to go near them now
would be suicidal.
で、引き返してきたとこにさっきの騒ぎってわけだ
That's why I turned back
and came across you two.
くそっ！武士ってのはなんでそんなに戦が好きなんだ！
Dang it, why do samurai
like to fight so much?
あ…うるさかったか、ごめん
Sorry, that was too loud, huh.
動くんじゃないよ 傷が開いちまう
Don't move, now. Your wounds will open up.
まったく…
Dear, dear.
穴ぐらに籠もった手負いの獣ってとこだね
You're like a wounded beast
hiding in his cave.
いいかい？これは人の声だ
Hear this? This is a human's voice.
周りにあるのは、森に生きてるモンや火や風の音さ
The other sounds are the creatures
in the woods, the fire, and the wind.
お前さんは慣れなきゃいけないよ！
You have to get used to it.
穴ぐらからこの世に出るためにはね！
To come out of your cave
and live in this world.
あにき…
Hyakkimaru.
怪我人なんだぞ？無理させんなって！
He's hurt. Don't force him like that.
あにきはまだ仏さんになるわけにはいかねぇんだからよ
He needs time to get used to it.
なんともしんとした声だねぇ…
What a gentle voice.
まだ動いちゃ危ないよ！
You shouldn't get up yet.
やれやれ…
Dear, dear.
…こんな固いの食えねぇよ
I can't eat this tough meat.
花　あかい花
Oh, the red flower
あの人の髪に
In her hair
咲いてゆれるだろう
It blooms and sways
お陽さまの…
Like the sun...
怪我してるの？大丈夫？
Are you hurt? Are you okay?
あぁ、見えてないのね
Oh, you can't see.
ほら、ここよ
See? I'm right here.
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
熱があるんじゃない？
You must have a fever.
こんな水の中に入っちゃダメ 早く出て！
You shouldn't be in the water. Come.
ちょっと、しっかりして！
Oh no, hang on there.
あにきー！
Hey!
こんなに弱っちまってるあにき、初めてだ…
I've never seen him so weak before.
まぁ怪我のせいもあるだろうが
It must be because of his wounds.
鬼神からいろんなモン取り戻したようだからねぇ
But he's also regained many things
from the demons.
頭がおっつかないのかもしれないよ
Maybe he's having trouble adjusting.
これ、古着解いたのだけど綺麗だから使って
Here are some old rags, but they're clean.
すまねぇ
-Thanks.
-Mio, was it?
ミオさん…だったか
邪魔しちまったうえに面倒かけて悪いねぇ
Forgive us for causing you
so much trouble.
そんなこと…治るまでいてもらって大丈夫だから
Not at all. Please stay until he's better.
いいのかい？
Can we?
もちろん ここには、あんたの兄さんみたいな子もたくさんいるから 安心して
Of course. There are lots of people here
like your big brother.
みんな慣れてるから
We're all used to it.
え？
Don't be shy, say hello kids.
みんな！こそこそしないで、ちゃんと挨拶しなさい！ほら
ひどい戦があってね…
There was a terrible war.
家も何も、全部なくなってしまって
We lost our houses and everything we had.
そんな者同士集まって暮らしてるの
So we all live together here.
じゃあ、みんなおとちゃんもおかちゃんも…
So none of them have dads or moms?
そ　でも、みんないい子
Right. But they're all wonderful children.
子供ばかりだって、なんとかなるもんね
We make do somehow,
even though they're all young.
あー、ミオ姉！まだ起きてんのか！
Sis Mio, you're still up?
ほら、どいたどいた！
Come out, out you guys.
ミオ姉、今のうちに寝とかねぇと身体もたねぇぞ！
Sis Mio, you better get some sleep
while you can.
怪我人は俺が面倒見っから、早く寝ろって
I'll watch over the hurt guy,
so you go to sleep.
わかったわかった！
Okay, okay.
じゃ、何かあったらこのタケ坊に聞いて
If you need anything, ask Takebo here.
早く！朝メシ用意してあるから ちゃんと食ってから寝るんだぞ
Hurry up. I made breakfast
so eat it before you sleep.
はいはい
I will, I will.
お前たちの朝メシもある
There's some for you guys, too.
芋粥だ 食え
Potato gruel. Eat up.
ど…どうも
T-Thanks.
なんか手伝うことねぇか？
You need help?
いいって お前は怪我人見てろ
Nah, you watch over your guy.
いや、タダで世話になるわけにはいかねぇ
I can't just sit here
and do nothing in return.
メシ代ぐらいは働くのが筋ってもんだ
At least let me work
for how much you feed us.
ほぉー けっこう感心じゃねぇか
You're a good guy, huh.
あにきあにきーってベソくてたくせに
Even though you cried like a baby
over your guy.
かいてねぇ！全然かいてねぇぞ、これっぽっちも！
I did not! Not even a drop.
しーっ！ミオ姉が起きちまうだろ！
Shh, you'll wake Sis Mio.
ごめん…でも、なんでこんな時間に寝てるんだ？
Sorry, but why is she sleeping now?
夜に働きに行ってんだよ
Because she works during the night.
酒井様の陣、いつ戦になるかわからねぇから
The Sakai army can't say
when the war might start up.
ひと晩じゅう誰かが起きてて、その世話がいるんだってさ
So somebody has to serve them
all through the night.
夜のほうが賃金がいいし
Besides, the pay is better
during the night.
ミオ姉は働きがいいから、食いモンも貰えるんだぞ
Sis Mio works hard,
so she even gets food.
だから昼間は寝かせてやらねぇと
So we have to let her sleep
during the day.
へぇー、お前もけっこう感心だな
You're a pretty good guy too, huh.
坊さん！どっか行くのか？
Where are you off to, Priest?
ああ 戦場を避けて通る道がないかと思ってね
I'm going to look for a path
where we can avoid the battlefield.
ちょいと行ってくるよ
I won't be gone long.
戻らなかったら獣道でもなんでも見つけたと思っとくれ　じゃ！
But if I don't return, it means I've found
some little path to sneak out of.
あぁ
Okay.
なんだ？連れじゃなかったのか？
Huh? He's not with you guys?
ときどき会うんだ 妙な坊さんでさ
We just meet sometimes. He's weird.
また戦になんのかなー…
I wonder if there's going to be
another war.
さぁ
Who knows?
ここも危ねぇな…くそっ
I guess we can't stay here either. Damn.
国境における酒井の陣には、未だ動きはなく 膠着状態が続いております
Sakai's army at the border
hasn't made a move. It's a deadlock.
このまま続くのであれば、新たに兵糧を送らねばならぬかと
If this lasts any longer,
we'll have to send more provisions.
その程度の蓄えはあろう
We must have enough for that.
はぁ…ただ
Yes, but...
もうひと月近く雨がございませぬ
It hasn't rained for almost a month now.
この時期、ここまで降らぬのは珍しきことなれば
It's uncommon to be so dry
during this season.
万が一の備えは必要かと
We should store up, just in case.
我が領土において共作などはありえん！
There will be no bad harvests on my land.
はぁ…
Sir...
そうでございましょうか
How can you be so sure?
奥！
My lady.
酒井殿のことに、此度の日照り続き
Trouble with Lord Sakai,
and now this drought.
それに、今年は山崩れもございました
We had a landslide this year, too.
まるで…かつてのこの国に戻ったような
It's like we've gone back to the past.
何が言いたい！
What are you saying?
わたくしどもは、国ごと小さないしずえひとつの上に乗っていることを
You, I, this domain.
We all sit atop a small cornerstone.
お忘れなきようにと
Please do not forget that.
いつ崩れてもおかしくはありませぬ
It could crumble and fall any day.
酒井ごとき小国
The hell with Sakai.
早々に片を付けるよう申し伝えよ！
-Take care of matters quickly.
-Yes, my lord.
はっ
せーいせいせいせーい！
Go, go, go!
ぞーいぞいぞいぞーい！
Swish, swish!
せーいせいせいせーい！ぐばぁっ！
あんたたち！
Kids.
笑ってないで手伝わなきゃ
Stop giggling and help out.
百鬼丸、具合はどう？
Hyakkimaru, how are you feeling?
まだ熱い…
You still have a fever.
そうだ 今夜、薬もらってくる！
I'll get you some medicine tonight.
酒井様の陣ならきっとあると思うから
I'm sure Lord Sakai's army has some.
じゃ、仕事行ってくるね！
I'll be going to work then.
あにき！もうちょっとしたら夕飯だってさ！
Supper will be ready in a bit.
赤い花つんで
Pick a red flower
あの人にあげよ
To give to her
あの人の髪に
In her hair
あにき…
You...
やっぱり安全な道は、お前さんたち獣のほうが知ってるねぇ
You creatures know the safe paths
better than us humans.
これなら…
This way, then.
こいつはいい場所だ…
This is quite a nice place.
どうしたの？こんなとこで
What are you doing out here?
薬？大丈夫
Medicine? Don't worry, here.
ほら、すぐに煎じて…
I'll brew it for you.
不思議ね…なんだか見えてるみたい
How strange. It feels like you can see.
ずっと奥のほうまで
Down deep inside of me.
見えてるよ　魂の色が
He can. He sees the color of your soul.
あにき、勝手に出歩くなよ
Don't you leave like that.
びっくりするだろ
You scared me.
魂の色？
Color of the soul?
うん  おいらもよくわかんねぇけど
Yeah, I don't get it very much either.
生きてるモンの魂がいろんな色で見えるんだってさ
But he can see the colors
of the souls of living things.
人だけじゃないぜ？草とか木とか獣とか  あやかしなんか一発でわかっちまう
Not just people. Grass, trees, animals.
He can find ghouls easily, too.
きっとすげー汚い色してんだろうなぁ
I bet they've got a really gross color.
そう…
I see...
なに？
What?
もしかして、姉ちゃんの歌が聞きたいんじゃ
Maybe he wants to hear you sing.
歌？
Sing?
あにき、姉ちゃんの歌はうるさくないみたいなんだよなぁ
Seems like your song doesn't bother him.
そうだ！姉ちゃんの歌聞いてれば、音に慣れるかも！
Hey! If he listens to you sing,
he'll get used to sound.
今のままじゃ、穴ぐらに籠もった獣みたいなもんだからな
He's like a hurt beast
in a cave right now.
姉ちゃんの歌で穴から引っ張り出してくれよ
Draw him out of it with your song.
私の歌、そんな大層なもんじゃないと思うけど…
My song isn't that great...
じゃあ…
Okay then.
赤い花つんで
Pick a red flower
の人にあげよ
To give to her
あの人の髪に
In her hair
この花さしてあげよ
I will put the flower
あら、お坊さん！
Oh, the priest.
抜け道、見つかんなかったのか
No paths out?
いや  ちょいとばかり、いい話と悪い話を持ってきた
Nah, I have some good news
and some bad news.
へぇ、そんないい土地があったのか！
Sound like a great place!
あそこなら、戦があったってそうそう焼け出されることはないだろうよ？
You'll be safe there even if a war starts.
ちとばかし舐めてみたが、土も悪くなさそうだ
I licked the soil, and it seemed good.
ミオ姉、行こうぜ！そこに住もう！
Let's go, Sis Mio. Let's live there.
う…うん
Yes...
喜ぶのは早いよ
But not so fast.
実はその土地には大家がいるのさ
Something already owns that land.
大家？いま空き地だって
But you said it was a vacant lot.
鬼神さ
A demon.
ありゃ相当だよ うかつに手を出すのは剣呑だ
It's not something
we want to mess with lightly.
なんだよ…
Aww, man.
鬼神って、化け物か？
You mean, a ghoul?
あぁ  ただのあやかしなんかよりよっぽど強いんだ
It's way stronger than
just any old ghoul.
そう…
I see.
おい、あにき！まさか鬼神退治に行くつもりか？
Hey, you're not going out there
to get it, are you?
待てよ！そんな足じゃ無理だって！
Wait, you can't with that injury.
坊さん！
Priest!
そのつもりで話したところはあるにせよ
Though I told you knowing you'd go there,
まさか怪我も治らないうちにとは思わなかったかねぇ
I didn't think you'd go
before your wounds are healed.
せっかちだね
You just can't wait, huh?
坊さん！あにきのこと頼むぞ！
Priest, take care of him for me!
私も…頑張ってみよう
I'll try harder, too.
危なっかしいねぇ
We really must watch over him.
え、敵の陣でも動くって…
You're going to work for the enemy, too?
酒井様の陣と敵の陣と掛け持ちってことか？
You mean, you're going to work
for both sides?
うん、今夜からでも
Yes, starting tonight.
無理だってそんなの！
That's too dangerous.
そうだよ、今だって大変なんだろう？
Yeah, it's hard enough on you already.
でも、新しいところに移るならちゃんと準備しなきゃ
But we need to get ready
to move to the new place.
土地だけあってもしょうがないでしょ？
We can't live on an empty lot.
そりゃそうだけど…
Yeah, but...
大丈夫！戦でたくさんなくしたぶん、戦から取り戻すだけ
Don't worry. War took a lot from us,
so let's get it back.
ミオ姉…
Sis Mio...
さ、そうと決まったらたっぷり寝とかないと！
I should rest up while I can.
それじゃ、おやすみ
Goodnight, then.
あぁ…
Yeah.
ミオ姉、こうと決めたら頑固だからなぁ…
Sis Mio's really stubborn
when she wants to be.
でも、酒井様の敵陣には荒くれ者が多いって聞くし…
But I heard the enemy is pretty rough.
よし！おいらがついてってやるよ！
Okay, I'll go with her.
お前が？だったら俺も…
You? Then I'll go too.
ダメダメ、お前はみんなの面倒見なきゃだろ？
No, you must stay with the other kids.
大丈夫、あんまり大変そうだったらやめさせる
Don't worry, if things get too tough,
I'll make her quit.
そっか…頼む
Okay, thanks.
戦から取り戻す…か
Take them back from war, huh.
いいじゃねえか おいらたちだって、侍から取ってやればいいんだ
I like that.
We'll take from the samurai, too.
ったく、いつまで睨めっこしてんだ
How long are we going to sit here?
これじゃ手柄の立てようがねぇ
I can't make a name for myself.
まったくだ こんなド田舎じゃあ、糞以外にすることねぇや
Yeah, nothing to do here but take a dump.
お兄さんたち
Sirs.
働かせてほしいんだけど
I'm looking for a job.
あれー、ミオ姉どこだ…？
Huh? Where'd Mio go?
わかるだろ？
You see?
大丈夫かい？
You sure about this?
まだやめといたほうがいいんじゃないかねぇ…
You should wait until you've healed.
あっちか！
That must be it.
今さね！
Now!
百鬼丸！
Hyakkimaru!
百鬼丸…お前さん…
Hyakkimaru, your voice...!
憂鬱が風に散らばり
Sorrow scatters in the wind,
吹き溜まって影になる
piling up to form shadows
僕らの足音は　無用を饒舌に諭す
Our footsteps admonish
indifference in such verbose ways
君の瞳の深さを覗き見て狼狽える
As I peek into your fathomless eyes,
I lose my composure
望みなどあったでしょうか　この行き先には
Is there any hope
in the place I am heading to?
戯けて笑うのは
I feign amusement and laugh
この道が暗いから
because this road is so dark
灯りを灯すのに　僕がいるでしょう
I will be there to shine the light
さよならごっこは慣れたもんさ
I'm used to playing at saying goodbye,
でも手を振ったら泣いちゃった
but I cried when I waved to you
僕らの真っ赤な悲しみが 暮れる 暮れる そして夜が来る
Our fiery woes fade... and fade...
until night falls upon us
当たり前にやってくる明日なら
If I knew tomorrow would be so mundane,
生きたいなんて言わなかった
I wouldn't have said that I wanted to live
よせばいいのに夢見てしまう 未来 未来 君のせいなんだ
I know it's futile but can't help dreaming
of a future... a future... you are to blame
"Yocho"